Hello everyone, my name is Hemant. You are watching this
video of the technical analysis series. Today
's stock that I have selected
for swing trading is ICICI
Lombard. At present, you are
seeing this chart in front of you. I have currently
placed it on the weekly time frame. Here I have
plotted the immediate resistance of 1295. The reason
behind marking this immediate swing is
very simple. You can see that
from this point the price has
faced rejection many times. If we see a
breakout of this swing in futures, then
we
can see ICICI Lombard coming up to the level of Rs. 1375 in futures. So,
when the reaction is created here on the chart,
you will see many indicators also
moving in your direction.
Now the first thing you will
see here is that I have
plotted an exponential moving average
whose length is given by  This is
my exponential moving average of 200.
If you look here on this weekly time
frame, if we add on the last 1, 2, 3, 4 and today's current price, then for
five weeks
continuously
we can see the price taking support above this moving average. This is the
first point. The second most
important thing is the explanation of this 200 period
moving average. The price has
broken the moving average by forming a very strong candle
and there is no resistance. This broken item
converts itself into support
and we will see the same support evidence being
formed here with the price action.
Now I will break this chart on another smaller time
frame here. So you will
see that a
range has developed in the market for a very long time and the
price has been consolidating within a tight range for a very long time. By
shortening the time frame a little, I would
like to show you here. So the
resistance that you will see here, if
I talk about it, then that  Resistance will
form around this level,
so we can conclude that the momentum
level of 1216 is creating
immediate resistance for us at this top.
Look, there's a very simple way to short this stock: if it gives you an
unbroken breakout and cooking. Given the
way the price action has developed here
and the time it has been
consolidating within this range, the
chances are very low that the stock will break
this range with a normal flat opening. It has
taken multiple times of
doing so, and each time it has faced upside
resistance. So, what I'm expecting is a
very strong probability that the
price will open a gap here and
break this resistance after a gap-up open.
If it gives you an unbroken breakout, if it provides you with a good breakout,
you can create a long position from here.
Your immediate
targets are going to be  1294 and as
we also studied it on the weekly time frame,
if it breaks the 1295 level,
then we
can also see targets up to 1375 in the coming time.
So now one more thing here, as I
told you, whenever a
specific price section is formed in the stock, because of our
responsibility, we must
plot the approaching indicator there. So,
look, here
I am plotting the closed indicator here. And you will see that
this stock has a very good
habitual pattern. And what is this
habitual pattern, you will see that whenever the price
consolidates, it struggles
and it keeps itself locked inside this so-called struggling jam for a very long time. So,
you can see that
a good period here, from November 16th to
November 24th, you can see that it has been a very
good period of consolidation. And when it has given you a very
strong
Breakout with this particular candle: Similar to the
formation we are
seeing where the price has been
struggling for a long time, we can see that
almost from the seventh of December the
range is also getting narrower,
its width is shrinking a lot, so if
seen from every angle and from the
perspective of an indicator also this
top is suggesting today it can provide us with a very
good breakout trade, so I am
bullish on this because right now
I see the price action becoming bullish, in
whichever direction the range breaks, we
enter in that direction with a rope rate top loss.
You must have liked today's video and
you must have also learned a lot from today's video.
If you like and see the video then do like and
subscribe.